altrec.com 2009-04-30

# Helpdesk: Privacy Policy - Altrec.com

**We will never sell, lease, rent or give your e-mail address or other personal information to anyone else without your permission.** Period. Since Altrec.com's distribution model requires some manufacturers to ship products to customers, it is necessary to provide shipping information for that purpose. We created this policy to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy.

* * *

The following policy is enacted to show Altrec.com's firm commitment to customer privacy.

We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is used to help identify you and your shopping cart and to gather broad demographic information. Our site uses cookies to keep track of your shopping cart. We use cookies for other purposes such as site personalization. You can reject cookies and still use the Altrec.com site, however, it will disable the ability for the site to recognize your cart, your account and any personalization efforts.

This site contains links to other sites. Altrec.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. Since Altrec.com's distribution model requires some manufacturers to ship products to customers, it is necessary to provide shipping information.

Our site uses an order form for customers to request information, products and services. We collect visitor's contact information including but not limited to addresses, email addresses, phone numbers and financial information (account or credit card numbers). Information is gathered by Altrec.com and its agent, Coremetrics, for the sole benefit of Altrec.com.

Contact information from the order form is used to send orders, information about our company, and promotional material from some of our partners to our customers. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the customer when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services.

Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information (typically the customer's email address) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level). We use contact data from our surveys to send the user promotional material from Altrec.com and at times, some of our partners. When partners will receive the customer's information, it will be disclosed as such. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We use this data to tailor our visitor's experience at our site, showing them content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences. 

We run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for contact information (typically the customer's email address) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level). We use contact data from our contests to send users promotional material from Altrec.com and at times, some of our partners. When partners will receive the customer's information, it will be disclosed as such. The customer's contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary (i.e. When someone wins a contest.) Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We use this data to tailor our visitor's experience at our site, showing them content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences. 

**Security**  
This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. When we collect sensitive information, it is done with our Secure Server (SSL). All employees are aware of security procedures and place the highest value on customers' privacy and security. For more information on our Security see the Your Information page.

**Subscriptions to Magazines**  
Altrec.com provides the opportunity for customers to purchase subscriptions to various publications. The information submitted will only be given to Altrec, Inc and the Publisher of the purchased magazine subscription. All use of information by Altrec.com will be within the guidelines set forth in Altrec.com's Privacy Policy. Altrec.com cannot vouch for the privacy policies of the Publisher(s) and does not control or monitor the use of entry information by the Publisher(s).

**Supplementation Information**  
This site supplements the information that you provide with information that is received from third parties.

**Choice/Opt-Out**  
Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about the visitor. 

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service.

**Changes to Customers' Accounts**  
Customers can change or delete their personal account information by going to the "My Account" section in the site, located in the navigation bar. Questions about accounts can be answered by the Customer Service group. Please send an email with your request to [customerservice@altrec.com](mailto:customerservice@altrec.com)

**Product Gear Reviews**  
When a customer writes a product Gear Review, the text of that review may also be published on Altrec.com, GreatOutdoors.com and other Altrec.com partner stores with the same products. The customer's name will only be shown if the customer chose not to remain anonymous when writing the Gear Review.

**Changes to Privacy Policy**  
Internet dynamics continually change and it is possible that the Privacy Policy could undergo slight changes, although any such changes would most likely be minimal. However, if any substantial changes are made to the policy, we will make every effort to notify customers through prominent notices on the site. This will include the following: prominent display in the "About Us" section of the site and links on other prominent locations around the site to direct customers to any changes. 

**Contacting Us**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you may contact [privacy@altrec.com](mailto:privacy@altrec.com) or: 

**Altrec.com**  
Attn: Customer Service- Privacy  
725 SW Umatilla Ave.  
Redmond, OR 97756
